let sciencequestions = {
    time: 30, // in minutes
    questions: [
        {
            question: "1. What is the chemical formula for water?",
            option1: "H2O",
            option2: "O2",
            option3: "CO2",
            option4: "H2SO4",
            correctresponse: "H2O",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "2. What is the speed of light in a vacuum?",
            option1: "300,000 km/s",
            option2: "150,000 km/s",
            option3: "500,000 km/s",
            option4: "100,000 km/s",
            correctresponse: "300,000 km/s",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "3. What planet is known as the Red Planet?",
            option1: "Venus",
            option2: "Mars",
            option3: "Jupiter",
            option4: "Mercury",
            correctresponse: "Mars",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "4. What is the powerhouse of the cell?",
            option1: "Nucleus",
            option2: "Ribosome",
            option3: "Mitochondria",
            option4: "Golgi apparatus",
            correctresponse: "Mitochondria",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "5. Which gas do plants primarily use for photosynthesis?",
            option1: "Oxygen",
            option2: "Nitrogen",
            option3: "Carbon dioxide",
            option4: "Hydrogen",
            correctresponse: "Carbon dioxide",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "6. Who proposed the theory of relativity?",
            option1: "Isaac Newton",
            option2: "Albert Einstein",
            option3: "Galileo Galilei",
            option4: "Nikola Tesla",
            correctresponse: "Albert Einstein",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "7. What is the largest organ in the human body?",
            option1: "Liver",
            option2: "Brain",
            option3: "Skin",
            option4: "Heart",
            correctresponse: "Skin",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "8. What is the boiling point of water at sea level?",
            option1: "90°C",
            option2: "100°C",
            option3: "120°C",
            option4: "110°C",
            correctresponse: "100°C",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "9. Which planet has the most moons?",
            option1: "Jupiter",
            option2: "Saturn",
            option3: "Uranus",
            option4: "Neptune",
            correctresponse: "Saturn",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "10. What is the smallest unit of matter?",
            option1: "Molecule",
            option2: "Atom",
            option3: "Electron",
            option4: "Quark",
            correctresponse: "Atom",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "11. Which scientist developed the laws of motion?",
            option1: "Isaac Newton",
            option2: "Albert Einstein",
            option3: "Marie Curie",
            option4: "Charles Darwin",
            correctresponse: "Isaac Newton",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "12. What type of blood cells fight infections?",
            option1: "Red blood cells",
            option2: "White blood cells",
            option3: "Platelets",
            option4: "Plasma",
            correctresponse: "White blood cells",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "13. What is the most abundant gas in Earth's atmosphere?",
            option1: "Oxygen",
            option2: "Carbon dioxide",
            option3: "Nitrogen",
            option4: "Helium",
            correctresponse: "Nitrogen",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "14. What is the study of plants called?",
            option1: "Botany",
            option2: "Zoology",
            option3: "Geology",
            option4: "Ecology",
            correctresponse: "Botany",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "15. What is the pH value of pure water?",
            option1: "7",
            option2: "8",
            option3: "6",
            option4: "5",
            correctresponse: "7",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "16. What is the chemical symbol for gold?",
            option1: "Au",
            option2: "Ag",
            option3: "Fe",
            option4: "Pb",
            correctresponse: "Au",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "17. What is the most common type of star in the universe?",
            option1: "Red dwarf",
            option2: "White dwarf",
            option3: "Blue giant",
            option4: "Neutron star",
            correctresponse: "Red dwarf",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "18. What is the SI unit of force?",
            option1: "Newton",
            option2: "Joule",
            option3: "Pascal",
            option4: "Watt",
            correctresponse: "Newton",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "19. What is the name of the process by which plants lose water through their leaves?",
            option1: "Respiration",
            option2: "Transpiration",
            option3: "Osmosis",
            option4: "Photosynthesis",
            correctresponse: "Transpiration",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "20. What is the chemical formula for table salt?",
            option1: "NaCl",
            option2: "KCl",
            option3: "NaHCO3",
            option4: "CaCl2",
            correctresponse: "NaCl",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "21. What is the primary source of energy for the Earth?",
            option1: "The Sun",
            option2: "The Moon",
            option3: "Geothermal energy",
            option4: "Fossil fuels",
            correctresponse: "The Sun",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "22. What is the hardest natural substance on Earth?",
            option1: "Diamond",
            option2: "Gold",
            option3: "Iron",
            option4: "Quartz",
            correctresponse: "Diamond",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "23. What is the main function of red blood cells?",
            option1: "Fighting infections",
            option2: "Carrying oxygen",
            option3: "Clotting blood",
            option4: "Digesting food",
            correctresponse: "Carrying oxygen",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "24. What type of rock is formed by cooling magma or lava?",
            option1: "Sedimentary rock",
            option2: "Igneous rock",
            option3: "Metamorphic rock",
            option4: "Fossil rock",
            correctresponse: "Igneous rock",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "25. What is the largest planet in our solar system?",
            option1: "Earth",
            option2: "Saturn",
            option3: "Jupiter",
            option4: "Mars",
            correctresponse: "Jupiter",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "26. What is the process by which cells divide called?",
            option1: "Photosynthesis",
            option2: "Mitosis",
            option3: "Fission",
            option4: "Meiosis",
            correctresponse: "Mitosis",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "27. What is the smallest planet in our solar system?",
            option1: "Mars",
            option2: "Mercury",
            option3: "Venus",
            option4: "Pluto",
            correctresponse: "Mercury",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "28. What is the process by which plants make their own food?",
            option1: "Respiration",
            option2: "Osmosis",
            option3: "Photosynthesis",
            option4: "Digestion",
            correctresponse: "Photosynthesis",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "29. What is the most abundant element in the universe?",
            option1: "Oxygen",
            option2: "Hydrogen",
            option3: "Carbon",
            option4: "Nitrogen",
            correctresponse: "Hydrogen",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "30. What is the study of the universe called?",
            option1: "Geology",
            option2: "Biology",
            option3: "Astronomy",
            option4: "Ecology",
            correctresponse: "Astronomy",
            time: 1,
        },
    ],
};

export default sciencequestions;
